In case you're not terribly familiar with XML, let's spend
如果你对 XML 还没有熟悉到如数家珍 我们就花点时间
a few minutes talking syntax. Even if you are familiar,
谈一谈语法 即使你对它已经比较熟悉
it might make sense to follow along with this little
再稍微复习复习也会很有意义
review. So in XML, elements are the basic building blocks
在 XML 中 元素就是构成 XML 文档的基本积木块
of an XML document. Now an XML element is composed
一个 XML 元素含有
of an open tag and a closed tag, now this
一个开始标记和一个结束标记
is some data drawn from the New York Times developer
这是从《纽约时报》API 开发者处摘录的一些数据
API Encourage you to have a look at this site.
鼓励大家看看这个网站
We are going to look at some data from the most
我们要来看一些从最受欢迎的 API 处获得的数据
popular API. These are for example articles that are most frequently
比如 这些是《纽约时报》读者 用电子邮件
emailed among readers of the New York Times. Okay, so
发送最多的文章
let's look at a couple of examples here. So, the first
我们来看几个例子 对于这个文档
thing that we might notice about this particular document is
我们可能首先会注意到的是
that we have some tags for num results or some elements
有一些 num 结果的标记 或者
that have to do with the number of results. So,
与结果数相关的一些元素
this is actually result set from having done a query to
这个实际是一个结果集 它来自一次
the most popular API and we've got a, an
针对最受欢迎的 API 的查询 并且我们得到了一个元素
element that tells us how many results were identified
该元素告诉我们 通过我们的查询 识别出了多少结果
by our query. And then the list of results
接下来是结果列表
follows. Now this happens to be a single result here.
这里凑巧是一个单一的结果
And we can see that this result begins right
我们可以看到该结果从这里开始
here with this open tag and closes right here
从这个开始标记开始 然后到这个
with this close tag. Okay. Now just as a
结束标记结束 好 再来看看
couple of other examples of the data within this particular
这条结论中数据的另外几个例子
result, we can take a look at the byline, note that
我们可以看看署名栏 注意
it's got a close tag, as well. And some of the
它也带有一个结束标记 还有一些
other elements, here if you note the title for example, this
其它元素 如果你注意这个标题的话会发现
happens to be an article about bedbugs. Okay. So, this provides an
它正好是一篇有关臭虫的文章 那么 这个例子
example using some really nicely named tags. We know what these
所用的名字非常棒 我们知道这些代表什么
mean. Now, there's another aspect of XML that we need to concern
现在 我们要了解 XML 的一个需要特别关注的方面
ourselves with especially given some of the exercises that we're going
因为我们将要做的一些练习会用到
to have. Later on. And those have to do with attributes for
这个稍后说 这些与 XML 元素的属性有关
XML elements. Now, this document provides a number of very
看这里 这个文档提供给了很多
nice examples of elements in XML. But what we don't
XML 中元素的很好的例子 不过这里缺乏的是
have here are any examples of attributes for any of
与所用的这些元素的属性相关的例子
these elements being used. So what I'd like to do here
所以我要做的就是
is talk about essentially the two types of data that
主要谈一谈我们将要看到的两种类型的数据
we're going to look at that have been encoded in XML. One
它们是在 XML 中编码的
is this more documented oriented type of XML, which is
一个是较为面向文档的 XML 类型
originally the type of data that XML was designed to encode.
这种类型最初是 XML 用来编码的数据类型
But then we can also take a look at
不过现在我们仍然可以看看
something like this. Okay, now this is actual data from
类似的数据 看 这是来自 OpenStreetMap 项目的实际数据
the OpenStreetMap project. This is a pretty close
这是 OpenStreetMap 中西贝尔蒙特大道
zoomed in view from OpenStreetMap of West Belmont
的较近距离视角图
avenue. Particularly the 1000 block. And you can see right
尤其是1000号街区 大家可以在这里看到
here, there's a Giardano's Restaurant here. Giardano's is a famous
有一家 Giardano's 餐厅 Giardano's 是芝加哥的一家
pizza chain in Chicago. So, this is data that is
著名的匹萨连锁餐厅 该数据主要来自于
essentially from a layer on top of that particular map.
该地图基础上的一个图层
This is data that is human created. So, users
该数据是人为创造的
of OpenStreetMap have actually added this data on
事实上是 OpenStreetMap 的用户在地图数据的基础上添加了这个数据
top of the map data. And what I want to point out here is that this is very much
这里我想要指出的是 这个数据
not document oriented. This is just data. Okay? And
非常的“不面向文档” 它只是数据 知道吗？
a lot of times you see HTML used in this
大家很多时候都会看到 HTML 以这种方式使用
way, you'll see that attributes are heavily used. So
你会看到属性被大量应用
in this particular example, this is the node that represents
那么在这个例子中 这个节点代表的是
the Giordano's restaurant. We can see that there is
Giordano's 餐厅 我们可以看到
a number of attributes specified for this particular element.
这里有很多针对这个元素的属性
Common among them are the latitude and longitude attributes
它们都具有经度和纬度属性
that this particular annotation applies to. So, essentially what
这些属性都适用于这条注释 因此 基本上
this data element provides is a mapping from geographic
这个数据元素提供的是地理坐标
coordinates to more common street address coordinates. Okay? So
到更为常用的街道地址坐标的映射 对吧？
this is a good example of attributes in XML
因此 这是个 XML 中属性的很好的例子
and there's one other thing that I want to point
我还想要指出一点
out here. And that is this type of tag here.
就是标签的类型
Now in this particular data they're doing something that I probably
在该数据中 它们会做一些
wouldn't do, but it is the type of thing that
我可能不会做的事情 不过作为数据科学家
you're going to see as a data scientist and likely already
你将来会看到这类东西 或许你们已经看到了
have. Essentially, they've just got a bunch of key value
基本上 它们已经具备有一系列关键值对
pairs that are encoded in something called a tag element. And,
这些关键值对被编码在所谓的标签元素中
in this case, none of these tag elements have a
在该情况下 这些标签元素都不具备
close tag. Instead, they use this special xml syntax where you
结束标签 相反 它们采用这种特殊的 xml 语法
can simply create what are called empty tags, that
你可以仅创建出所谓的空标签
is tags that don't have any content. All of
即没有内容的标签
the data for this type of tag is contained
这种类型的标签的所有数据
directly within its attributes. So the most emailed example
是直接包含在其属性中的 这个电子邮件中使用最多的例子
here provides us a nice example of document oriented
是一个很好的面向文档的
XML with lots of content inside the elements. And
元素中含很多内容的 XML 的例子
this particular example from your OpenStreetMap project provides us
这个 OpenStreetMap 项目中的例子告诉我们
with other end of this spectrum which is very
光谱的另一端是非常面向数据的 XML
data oriented XML where all or almost all of the data
其中所有或几乎所有数据
is contained within attributes for the individual elements and in this
都包含在单个元素的属性中
types of cases, you often have mostly or at least many
在这种情况下 你看到的 XML 数据中 大多数会是空元素
empty elements within the XML data that you are looking at.
或者至少很多都是空元素